（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜地球は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
滅びゆこうとしていた＞
＜人類滅亡まで　あと１年＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　希望を求め→
１６万８０００光年のかなた
イスカンダルへ向け　旅立った＞
＜ヤマトは　途中
ガミラス冥王星前線基地を撃破＞
＜太陽系を離れ　ついに
外宇宙へと艦を進めていた＞
Garmillas
Beloved citizens of the Great Garmillas Empire,
（デスラー　ガミラス語で）
I know the crown of glory on my head
is a gift made possible by your loyalty
to the nation and to this planet, to Great Garmillas.
（歓声）
I name you my friends,
（デスラー）
and I am grateful to all of you for gathering here today.
Thank you.
（歓声）
（一同・ガミラス語）
Ghale Garmillon!! Ghale Desler!
Ilun Phuzeron.
（セレステラ　ガミラス語で）
You wrote a good speech.
（デスラー）よい原稿だったよ。
（セレステラ）お褒めに預かり　光栄です。
You honor me.
（デスラー）よい原稿だったよ。
（セレステラ）お褒めに預かり　光栄です。
（デスラー）人間とは
愚かで　従順な生き物だ。→
Humans are foolish and submissive creatures.
（デスラー）人間とは
愚かで　従順な生き物だ。→
And more than anything, they bore me.
そして
このうえなく退屈な存在でもある。
Your post-speech entertainment is ready.
このあと
余興の準備も　整っております。
Miezela Celestella Propaganda Minister
（デスラー）例の艦だね。
はい。
That ship?
Yes.
（拍手）
Lord Abelt Desler
（ヒス）
総統。　ガミラス帝国　建国１０００年→
Your Lordship,
Vice-Commander Redof Hyss
on behalf of your staff, I congratulate you on the 1000 years of Garmillas history,
ならびに
デスラー紀元１０３年を→
as well as the 103rd year of your reign.
閣僚を代表して
お祝い申し上げます。
Thank you, Vice-Commander.
（デスラー）ありがとう　副総統。
The Great Garmillas Empire
（ヒス）宇宙に冠たる　大ガミラスは→
has succeeded in uniting both the Large and Small Magellanic Clouds,
大小マゼラン統一という
偉業を成し遂げ→
and has expanded into the Milky Way.
天の川銀河へと進出。→
The Empire's territory continues to expand,
帝国の版図は　ますます広がり→
and your glory shines down, across the entire universe.
総統の威光は　あまねく宇宙に→
降り注いでおります。
（タラン）同化政策も→
Our unification policy is working, as well.
順調に進んでおります。→
Velte Talan Armaments Minister
帰順を示した者には→
Those that submit to us are allowed to contribute to the Empire
滅亡ではなく
二等臣民としての権利を。→
as second-class Garmillans, rather than be destroyed.
これが
帝国繁栄の礎となっております。
Truly a mighty deed!
（ゼーリック）まさに偉業！→
Truly the act of a god.
まさに　神の御業である。　総統と→
No enemy can
withstand the might of His Lordship and the Great Garmillas armies!
我が大ガミラスの向かう所
敵なし。
Herm Zoellik Inspector-General of the Central Army
Garmillas is invincible! We will never be defeated!
無敵ガミラス　敗れることなし！
Arrogance is a mistake.
（ディッツ）慢心はなりませんぞ。
ん？
（ディッツ）小マゼラン外縁部では→
We must remain wary of
Gul Ditz Supreme Commander of Astrofleets
the barbarian invaders from outside the galaxy around the Small Magellanic Cloud.
外宇宙からの
蛮族侵入も　予断を許しません。
Admiral Ditz!
ディッツ君！　君は　我が輩が→
Are you calling me a boaster?
大ぼら吹きだとでも？
As the Commander of the Astrofleets, I speak the truth.
（ディッツ）艦隊運用の責任者として→
事実を申し上げている。
Ghader Talan Vice-Chief of the General Staff
Your Lordship,
（ガデル）総統　その蛮族どもも
程なく　一掃されることでしょう。
we will eliminate these barbarians soon.
I've dispatched Senior General Domel.
（ディッツ）ドメル中将を派遣しました。
The Space Wolf?
（デスラー）宇宙の狼か。
I'm sure he will live up to our expectations.
彼なら
期待に応えてくれることだろう。
くっ…。
（デスラー）諸君。　今宵は→
Everyone, I've prepared some entertainment to help you
諸君の日頃からの
労をねぎらうため→
forget the stress of your difficult jobs.
ちょっとした余興を用意した。
Tonight, you will watch video from the front lines of the Empire's war.
今宵は　皆様方に→
帝国最前線の映像を
ご覧いただきます。
（ギムレー）
なぜ　そんなものを？
Why would we watch that?
Heydom Gimleh Imperial Guard Information Officer
（セレステラ）それは
ご覧いただく作戦を→
Because His Lordship created the plan you are about to see in execution.
総統ご自身が
立案されたからですよ。
Very well, everyone, let us begin the game.
では　諸君　ゲームを始めよう。
[外:6481AA074865672B97996C8989BEC66F]
When you wish upon a star,
[外:6481AA074865672B97996C8989BEC66F]（百合亜）
星に願いをかけるなら…→
if your heart is in your dream,
それを　心を込めて願うなら→
あなたの願いは　かなうでしょう。→
no request is too extreme,
when you wish upon a star as dreamers do.
それを　心で　夢見ましょう。→
Like a bolt out of the blue, fate will come, and see you through.
そして　そうやって運命は→
思いもかけないところから
やってくるものなのです。
（新見）はぁ…。
YRA Radio Yamato.
（百合亜）「ＹＲＡラジオヤマト」→
次の放送は
艦内時間２０時３０分からです。→
Our next broadcast will be at local time 20:30.
This has been Yuria Misaki.
お相手は　岬百合亜でした。
And that's a wrap.
（ミキサー）はい　オッケー。
（百合亜）う～ん…。　ん？
んん…。→
Are you sure it's okay for you to kill time here?
いいの？
あんた。　こんな所で　油売ってて。
Yeah, I'm off now.
（星名）うん。　今　オフだからね。
ふ～ん。
（星名）そういえば知ってる？
えっ？
Hey, did you know...
There's a door up here that never opens.
この先に　開かずの間があってさ→
And supposedly, a ghost is there. The ghost of a beautiful woman.
そこに出るらしいよ…
きれいな女の人の幽霊が。→
す～っと…。
それ　地球で　よく見た。
- It just suddenly appears--
- I saw that all the time on Earth.
えっ？
私　見える体質だから。
I see those things.
えっ!?　えっ…。
そうなんだ。
You do?
（太田）ヤマトは現在
地球より　約８光年の→
The Yamato is currently around 8 light years from Earth,
シリウス星系を
１８エスノットで航行中。
traversing the Sirius System at 18 s-knots.
We'll be jumping 12 light years in our next warp.
（真田）次のワープでは
１２光年を跳躍。→
グリーゼ５８１に達する予定です。
That should take us to Gliese 581.
12 light years?
（沖田十三）１２光年か…。
This will be our last chance to see Earth through the Yamato's VLBI telescope.
ヤマトのＶＬＢＩ望遠鏡で
あの地球の姿を見られる→
最後の機会だな。
（３人）あっ…。
Sanada.
真田君。
（真田）はい。
Yes, sir.
ピッピッピッピッ（キーボード操作音）
（一同）ああっ。
- Is that...
- ...the Earth?
（島）これは…。
（南部）地球か？
（真田）ここは
太陽系から８．６光年。
We are 8.6 light years from the Solar System.
つまり　これは→
In other words, this is how Earth looked eight years ago.
およそ８年前の地球の姿だ。
（古代進）
ガミラスの侵略を→
Before Garmillas attacked it?
受ける前の地球か…。
Everyone, look well.
みんな　よく見ておけ。
This is Earth as it used to be, the Earth we're fighting to reclaim.
これが　我々が取り戻すべき
本来の地球だ。
Shima, prepare for warp.
島　ワープ準備に入れ。
Roger, preparing for warp.
（島）了解。　ワープ準備に入ります。
（観測兵）ヤマト　ジャンプしました。
Yamato has jumped.
ID the jump coordinates.
（ガンツ）ジャンプ座標を特定しろ。
Beginning space-time wave motion calculations.
（観測兵）時空間波動　計測開始。
（航宙士）空間航跡→
Tracing space wake.
トレース。
（通信兵）少佐殿→
Rear Brigadier!
友軍の補給艦が
ランデブーを求めてきています。
Friendly resupply ship requests a rendezvous.
Daddy, finish your work soon, and come home, okay?
（ヒルデ）お父さん　お仕事
早く終わらせて帰って来てね。
Mom's worried...
お母さんも
お父さんを心配してるの。→
だって　お父さん…。
（シュルツ）総統は我らに→
Lord Desler ordered us to fight and die.
戦って死ねと
仰せられた。
I'm sorry, Hilde.
すまない…　ヒルデ。
ピピッ（受信音）
（ガンツ・通信）シュルツ司令！→
Commander Schultz, General Goer's resupply has arrived.
ゲール将軍から
支援物資が届きます！
ん？　あぁ…。→
まさか…　本当か!?
No way... Is that true?
Yes, we were not abandoned, after all!
（ガンツ・通信）はい！
我々は　見捨てられたわけでは→
なかったのです。
あぁ…。
（ゲール）銀河方面　作戦司令長官の
ゲールであります。→
Garemud Goer Galactic Theater Commander
Galactic Theater Commander Goer, sir!
今回　総統が
ご立案された作戦の→
I am honored to be the commanding officer for the operation Your Lordship designed.
現場指揮を
担当させていただけること→
誠に光栄。
もういい。　ゲール君→
That's enough.
Goer, what became of the thing I sent you?
君に送ったものは
どうなったのかね？
Yes, sir! I'm sorry! The new torpedo...
（ゲール）はっ！　失礼いたしました。
例の新型魚雷は…。
（セレステラ）デスラー魚雷。
（ゲール）あっ…　わっわっ　その…→
The Desler Torpedo...
Yes, the Desler Torpedo!
デスラー魚雷は　すでに→
We have already deployed it on the front lines.
前線配備を完了いたしております。
Warp complete.
（森雪）ワープ終了。
グリーゼ５８１星系に入りました。
We are in the Gliese 581 System.
We are 20.4 light years from the Earth.
ここは　地球から２０．４光年。→
That's the primary star, Gliese 581, a red dwarf star.
あれが主星
赤色矮星のグリーゼ５８１だ。
（佐渡）ふむ…。　ワープの影響は→
Looks like the warp hasn't had any negative effects.
なさそうですな。　ですが→
But be careful.
くれぐれも　無理は
せんでくださいよ。
≪コン　コン（ノック）
（新見）新見情報長　入ります。
This is Intelligence Officer Niimi. I'm coming in.
Okay, take care.
（佐渡）じゃあ　お大事に。
We'll be going, then.
（真琴）では　お先に失礼しま～す。
（新見）よろしいですか？
Is this a good time?
It's fine.
かまわんよ。　なんだね？
What is it?
This system has a planet suitable for the human-colonization plan.
この星系には　人類移住計画の
対象惑星があります。
I'd like permission to form an expedition to investigate it.
調査隊を編成して
その可能性を調べる許可を。
我々に　そんな余裕はない。
We don't have the time.
Of course that's true, but...
それは　もちろん　そうですが…→
人類が生き延びるためには
一つでも多くの選択肢が→
But don't we need all possible options, if humanity is going to survive?
必要なのではないでしょうか!?
Niimi, the Izumo Plan was scrapped.
新見君
イズモ計画は　破棄されたのだよ。
でも　それは…。
But that was...
ドドーン！
（２人）あっ！
（太田）左舷　衝撃　加わる。
（島）船体復元。→
Port side has been hit.
Righting the ship. Tilting fifteen degrees.
１５度　戻す。
（相原）電子機器の一部に作動異常。
あっ！
Some electronics are off line.
（ＡＵ０９）強力ナ
荷電粒子ノ波動ヲ　検知。
Detecting a powerful charged-particle wave motion.
Ahead slow. Red 20!
（島）
両舷　前進微速。　赤２０。
これは…。
状況を　報告せよ。
What is this?
Report!
どうやら　超高密度の
プラズマ・フィラメントに→
It seems we've run into a hyper-dense plasma filament field.
接触したようです。
なんですか？　それ。
What are those?
Plasma flares being emitted by a star.
恒星から放射されている
フレアプラズマの束だ。
（真田）つまり　太陽風だよ。→
A solar storm, in other words.
Our ship has run into the edge of one of the plasma corridors.
本艦は　そのプラズマ回廊の壁面に
接触してしまった。
だが　これは異常だ。
理論値の数億倍の→
But this isn't normal.
Birkeland currents are several hundred million times their theoretical values.
ビルケランド電流が流れている。
どういうことです？
What does that mean?
It means this has clearly been artificially created.
明らかに人為的なもの…
ということだよ。
The rat has fallen into the trap!
（ゲール）ネズミが　罠に掛かりました。
I, Goer, am terribly impressed that you predicted they would come to this system!
この星系に　彼奴めが来るのを
予想されるとは　このゲール→
感服しました。
なに…→
It's nothing. I thought it might be amusing to analyze their ship's course.
暇潰しに　彼らの航路パターンを
解析してみてね。
The fun is just beginning.
お楽しみは　これからだよ。
Everyone, let us have a toast to cheer our Terron friends on.
では諸君　テロン人の健闘を祈って
乾杯しようではないか。
≪がはははっ！　これは愉快！→
Hilarious!
罠に落としておいて
健闘を祈るかぁ～？→
Set a trap for them, and then cheer them on?
総統も相当　冗談がお好きで。
ひっく！→
Your Lordship does enjoy his jokes!
がはははっ！
ピン
うわぁ～！
（一同）あっ！
ガミラスに　下品な男は不要だ。
Garmillas has no need of such disgusting men.
（一同）ガーレ・デスラー！
総統　万歳！
Ghale Desler!
Hail to our Leader!
（真田）電子機器の修復は
なんとかなりました。
I have electronics back on line.
ですが　そう何度も
あれに触れると　もちません。
But we won't be able to contact them too many times.
Calculate the range of plasma amplification.
プラズマの増幅範囲を計測。
Find a weak point in the corridor.
回廊の緩衝地帯を割り出せ。
必ず　どこかにあるはずだ。
It should be somewhere out there.
うっ　うぅ…。
３時の方向に
プラズマが微弱な領域あり。
Plasma gets weaker at three o'clock.
緩衝地帯と思われます。
It's probably a weak spot.
ビィー（警告音）
後方に　重力場のゆがみ。
There's a distortion in the gravity field, to our rear.
Something's warping out.
ワープアウト反応です。
んん…。
Torpedo loaded!
（兵）装填　完了。
デスラー魚雷　発射！
Fire the Desler Torpedo!
ビシュー！
敵艦　魚雷　発射。
Enemy ship has fired a torpedo!
迎撃不可能域まで　あと２０秒。
20 seconds until out of interception range.
捕捉した。　対空戦闘　用意。
Locked.
AA System ready.
（南部）魚雷戦　迎撃準備よし。
Ready to intercept torpedo.
13 seconds.
あと１３秒。　迎撃不可能域まで→
Prepare to intercept.
Time until out of interception range:
あと１０　９　８　７…。
艦長！
10. 9. 8. 7.
Captain!
６　５　４　３…。
6. 5. 4. 3.
艦尾魚雷発射管　開け。
Open the firing tubes along the ship's stern!
2. 1.
Fire!
撃てぇ～！
ドォーン！
命中。　目標の迎撃に成功。
Hit. We've intercepted the target.
はぁ…。
待ってください！
Wait a moment!
これは…。
What's this?
（シュルツ）これは…　なんだ？
What is this?
（通信兵）
帝星司令部に　映像　送ります。
Sending video to Imperial Command.
（一同）おお…。
（ゼーリック）これは　何事であるか!?
What is this?
Did you see that? That is the Desler Torpedo.
見たかね？
これが　デスラー魚雷の正体だ。
Is that gas?
（ヒス）あれは　ガスでございますか？
（セレステラ）
ミルベリア星系で発見された→
Originating in the Mirbelia System,
it is an autonomous, self-replicating gas-based life form.
自立型自己複製システムを持つ→
ガス生命体です。
物質のエネルギーを変換→
It converts, unites, and absorbs material energy, enabling indefinite expansion.
同化　吸収して　無限に増殖する→
The ultimate in chemical weapons.
まさに　究極の化学兵器です。
（一同）おお～！
ネズミ捕りの中に→
I threw a cat into the rat trap.
猫を１匹　放り込んでみたのだ。
Unidentified object's energy readings are rising.
（太田）
未確認物体　エネルギー増加。
Keep an eye on it.
観測を続けろ。
（真田）
プラズマを吸収し　増殖している。
It's absorbing the plasma and growing.
接触すれば　ヤマトも
分解　吸収されてしまいます。
If we come into contact with it, we'll be broken down and absorbed.
んん…。
未確認物体　距離を縮めてきます。
The unidentified object is approaching us.
文字どおり　袋のネズミ。
Just like a rat in a trap, indeed. Now we just wait for the cat to kill it.
あとは
猫が始末してくれる寸法ですな。
いや　出口を１つ　用意してある。
No, I've prepared an exit for them.
島　測定したプラズマ緩衝地帯は
抜けられそうか？
Shima, can we make it through that weak point you found in the plasma?
（島）なんとか　いけます。
待ってください。→
I believe so.
Wait.
このまま　緩衝宙域を進むと…。
If we keep going, through that area...
うそだろ…。
No way.
However, a giant star waits, mouth open, at the exit.
（デスラー）だが　出口の先には→
巨大な恒星が
その口を開けて　待っている。
ガスに食われるか→
Will they be consumed by gas or disintegrated in a burning fusion reactor?
灼熱の溶鉱炉で　溶けて消えるか→
彼らの運命は　ほかにあるかね？
Or is there another fate for them?
No other, of course. It is perfect, Your Lordship.
（ヒス）あるはずがございません。
完璧です　総統。
Everyone, let us applaud the brave decision they're about to make.
諸君　これから
彼らが下す勇気ある決断を→
拍手でたたえようじゃないか。
まさに
前門の虎　後門の狼ってやつか。
We can't go forward or back, can we?
Shima, full speed ahead, toward the star.
島　恒星に向け　最大戦速。
えっ　恒星に突っ込むんですか!?
Are we going to ram into the star?
Full speed ahead! Steady as she goes!
最大戦速　よ～そろ～！
（デスラー）どうやら　テロン人は→
It appears the Terrons have chosen to commit suicide by fire.
焼身自殺の道を　選んだようだな。
（拍手）
（太田）艦外温度１１００度。→
Temperature outside the ship is 1100 degrees.
艦内９０度。　更に　上昇中！
Inside, 90 degrees and rising!
環境制御システム
防熱処理　追いつかない。
Environmental control systems unable to moderate the temperature.
Captain, why don't we engage the Wave Motion Shield?
艦長　波動防壁を
張ってはいかがでしょう？→
At this rate, the ship's temperature will exceed the limit.
このままでは　艦内温度が
限界を超えてしまいます。
There's no need.
その必要はない。
総員　船外服を着用。
Everyone, put on your environmental suits.
Keep energy expenditure to a minimum as we advance.
このまま　エネルギー消費を
最小限に進むのだ。
防御隔壁　閉鎖。
Seal the bulkheads.
What about the Garmillas ship?
後方のガミラス艦は？
ガス状物体　後方→
It's 8000 behind the gas. It's following us.
距離８０００。
ぴったり　ついてきています。
うむ。　監視を怠るな。
Keep a close eye on it.
うっ！　んん…。
≫ドサッ
ん？　あっ…。　艦長！
Captain!
（佐渡）えらいこっちゃ～！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（百合亜）総員　船外服を着用…。
Oh, no!
All crew, put on your environmental suits
Doctor, you need to put this on!
（真琴）先生　これ　これ～！
（佐渡）なんじゃい!?
Repeat: All crew, put on your environmental suits.
Captain!
（佐渡）艦長～！
（真琴）うわっ！
（佐渡）って…　ん？
なんちゅう所に飛び込むんじゃ！→
Why the heck are we running toward that?!
すぐ引き返さんかい！
艦長を殺す気か!?　お前ら～！
Turn us around now!
Are you trying to get the captain killed?
大丈夫だ。
ちょっと　古傷が痛んだだけだよ。
It's okay.
My old wounds are just bothering me a little.
Right, Doctor?
そうですな？　先生。
えっ…　いや～　それじゃ　一応…→
Well, let me have a look, just to be on the safe side...
ええ～　お手を拝借。→
Pulse is normal.
脈も正常じゃな…。
こりゃ　大したことありませんな。
No problems at all!
Just some work-induced fatigue...
過労でしょう。　まあ　栄養剤でも→
Guess I'll give you a nutrient injection.
注射しておきましょうかねぇ。
はぁ…　よかった。
Good.
んんっ！
わしは　あんたの親友から→
I've been asked to keep you alive!
くれぐれもと頼まれとる。
言うことは
聞いてもらわにゃ　困りますぞ。
You need to listen to my orders.
Your condition...
あんたの体は…。
分かっているよ　先生。
I'm well aware, Doctor.
（太田）
前方　ＦＫ２２３に　紅炎発生。
Solar prominence straight ahead, at SK223.
（島）と～りか～じ！
Steer to port.
Captain, there's a change in the gas behind us!
艦長！
後方のガス状物体に変化あり。
It's trying to absorb the star, and it's being absorbed in turn.
（真田）恒星を同化しようとして
逆に　飲み込まれている。→
なるほど。　艦長は　これを
ねらっていらしたわけですね。
I see... So this is what the captain was after, right?
（一同）おおっ…。
（ゲール）この無能め！　貴様は→
You incompetents!
Were you just sitting and watching, as His Lordship's gas was devoured?
総統のガスが　焼かれていくのを
指をくわえて見てたのか!?→
この役立たずの劣等人種が！→
You useless, inferior races!
The entire responsibility for this rests with you, okay?
いいか？　責任はすべて
貴様にあるのだからな！→
You'd better believe I'll be reporting that to His Lordship!
総統へは
そう報告させてもらうから→
覚悟しと…。
あっ。
本艦は　これより　ヤマトへ向け→
This ship will now make a final run at the Yamato.
最後の突撃を敢行する。
We go with Brigadier Schultz!
シュルツ大佐と共に！
（一同）シュルツ大佐と共に！
We go with Brigadier Schultz!
Something's happened! A massive flare in front of us!
（太田）イレギュラー　発生！
前方に　巨大なフレアです。
（一同）あっ！
よけられないのか!?　島！
Can't we dodge it, Shima?
No, it's too big. We can't evade it!
ダメだ　大きすぎる！
回避できない。
針路そのまま。　古代→
Maintain course.
Kodai, hit the flare with the Wave Motion Gun.
波動砲で　フレアを撃て。
Yes, sir.
はい…　えっ？
フレアを撃つんでありますか？
Hit the flare?
復唱　どうした!?
は…　はい！
Repeat that order!
Y-Yes, sir!
フレアを　波動砲で撃ちます。
We'll hit the flare with the Wave Motion Gun.
（南部）波動砲への回路　開く。
Opening circuit to Wave Motion Gun.
Shutting all emergency valves.
非常弁　全閉鎖。→
Releasing safety lock.
安全装置　解除。
強制注入機　作動。→
Activating force injector.
Tachyon particle pressure rising in chamber.
薬室内　タキオン粒子　圧力上昇。→
８０　８５　９０…。
80%.
85%.
90%.
後方　敵艦　急速接近！
Enemy ship rapidly approaching behind us!
ピシュ　ピシュ　ピシュ　ピシュ！
ドォーン！
（一同）うわっ！
（太田）右舷に被弾！
構うな！
Hit to starboard!
Ignore them!
Ten seconds before we're too close!
接触限界点まで　あと１０秒。
エネルギー充填　１２０％。
Energy charge 120%!
波動砲　撃てぇ～！
Firing Wave Motion Gun!
バシューー!!
Head straight through that opening. Maintain course!
このまま　開口部を突破する。
針路そのまま～！
（兵）ヤマト　プロミネンスを突破！
（兵）艦内温度３００万ベク！
Yamato has broken through the solar prominence!
Ship temperature is 3,000,000 bek!
（シュルツ）バカな…。
（兵）耐熱限界点　超えます！
Impossible!
Our ship can't handle this heat!
（兵）艦尾融解！　操舵不能！
Stern is melting.
We've lost control!
（ガンツ）ザルツ　万歳～！
（一同）ザルツ　万歳！
Glory to Zaltz!
ドオォーーン!!
（親衛隊員）
映像信号　途絶しました。
Video signal lost.
（一同）あぁ…。
（ゲール）あっ…。→
Your Lordship! All responsibility for this failure rests with Schultz...
そ…　総統　これは
すべて　あのシュルツめの失態で→
その～　私めは…。　あっ…。
And I...
ピン
（ゲール）あら？
いやはや　諸君
見事な戦いぶりだったじゃないか。
Was that not a splendid battle, everyone?
これはこれで
なかなか楽しいゲームだったよ。
It was quite an entertaining game.
ヒス君。
（ヒス）はっ。
Hyss...
Sir!
（デスラー）戦死した者は　２階級　特進。
The dead are to be awarded a two-rank promotion.
遺族には
名誉ガミラス臣民の権利を→
Give their families honorary Garmillan status.
与えてやりたまえ。
ザー・ベルク！
Zar Belk!
では　今宵は
これで　お開きとしよう。
That will be all for this evening.
（デスラー）おやすみ　諸君。
（一同）ガーレ・デスラー！
Good night, everyone.
Ghale Desler!
Oh, one more thing, Celestella...
（デスラー）そうそう　セレステラ→
あのテロンの艦は
なんという名だったかな？
What was the Terron ship's name?
（セレステラ）確か　ヤマトだったと。
I believe it was called the "Yamato."
ふっ　ヤマトか。
記憶に　とどめておこう。
The Yamato?
I shall remember that.
（タラン）んん…。
ん？　どうされました？
What's wrong?
フレアをなぎ払った　あの武器→
That weapon that broke through the flare...
兵器開発局で試作中のものと
似ている。
It's similar to the prototype that Weapons Development is working on.
（ガデル）本当か？　兄さん。
（セレステラ）まさか…。
Is that true, Velte?
Impossible.
[外:6481AA074865672B97996C8989BEC66F]
[外:6481AA074865672B97996C8989BEC66F]（百合亜）今宵も
空の星々に　願いをかけましょう。→
Let's wish upon a star again tonight.
Trust our wishes to the stars, like dreamers do.
夢追う人がするように→
星に　思いを託しましょう。→
When you wish upon a star,
あなたが　心を込めて願えば→
your dreams come true.
夢は　必ず　かなうはずです。→
お相手は　岬百合亜でした。
This has been Yuria Misaki.
≫シューン（ドアの音）
Episode 8: Wish Upon a Star
Garmilloids are the Garmillas's vanguard.
Are the words spoken by the one we captured the truth, or falsehood?
Does the answer lie beyond communication between machines?
What is a person? What is a machine? And, what is a heart?
Next time: Clockwork Prisoner.
There are 339 days left before humanity is extinct.
今年１月のバッテリーの出火トラ
ブル以降停止されていた
ボーイング７８７の運航が今日、
全日空の新千歳－羽田の
臨時便から再開された。